# ALI YAZDI

Dept. Computer Engineering Amirkabir University, Hafez Ave., Tehran, Iran ma.yazdi75@gmail.com • ma.yazdi75@aut.ac.ir • +98 (912) 037-1375 • aliyazdi.tech

#### ABOUT ME

I have been working as a Flutter developer and mobile team leader for two years. A Software Engineering graduate who interests in using Artificial Intelligence and Software Engineering in my work experiences. An open-source advocate who helps developers to solve their problems in development. I am looking for a better opportunity and willing to relocate anywhere.

#### WORK **EXPERIENCE**

#### Mate Machine Inc., Vancouver, Canada - Remote

Jun 2020 - Present

#### Flutter Developer

- Mate Machine is a dating social media startup company that currently is in stealth mode.
  - R&D about Flutter's best architecture design for the current requirements.
  - Implementing SignalR socket client and full-featured social media chat.
  - Handling unique Firebase notifications for each user.
  - Supporting other Firebase distribution plugins like Analytics and Crashlytics.
  - Implementing P2P WebRTC video chatting.

#### Tarafdari, Tehran, Iran

Mar 2019 - May 2020

#### Mobile Application Developer • >

- Tarafdari is the first and most popular sports social media network with millions of users in Iran, providing official news and live scores of national and international matches.
  - R&D about Flutter framework as the migrating framework for the android application.
  - Developing requirement APIs for the application in Drupal.
  - Implementing the requirement plugin for the application media notification.
  - Adding features like downloadable multimedia content, live score matches, and social media profiles.
  - Implementing TV Sports matches streaming with Live Chat on the SocketIO.
  - Supporting Firebase distribution plugins like Notifications, Analytics, and Crashlytics.
  - Reaching more than 200k active users with less than 0.3% crashes on the Google Play Store and the local stores.

## **EDUCATION**

#### Amirkabir University of Technology, (Tehran Polytechnic), Tehran, Iran

Sep 2015 - Jan 2020

- Bachelor of Engineering (BSc.) in Computer Engineering, Software, Ranked 1st in Iran.
  - Thesis: Designing and Implementing Location Based Social Network Recommendation System
  - · Adviser: Prof. Mohammad Rahmati

#### Adab High School. Tehran, Iran

Sep 2011 - Jun 2014

■ Diploma in Mathematics and Physics, GPA: 19.31 / 20.00

#### **HONORS & AWARDS**

- Most installed sport application in Iran for Tarafdari application May 2020 • We could reach more than 200k active users on the Google Play Store after migrating to Flutter.
- First Place in the 12th Iran Web and Mobile Festival (IWMF)

Feb 2020

- For the Best Sport Mobile Application among 7k applications.
- Ranked in top 0.2% among more than 180K participants

Jul 2015

- In Nation-Wide University Entrance Exam among all Iranian Student of Physics and Mathematics.
- Qualified for the Second Round of Olympiad among more than 70K participants

• In the Iranian Physics Olympiad and Mathematical Olympiad.

Jul 2013

#### TECHNICAL **SKILLS**

- Programming Languages
  - Dart, Python, Java, C/C++, PHP, Assembly
- Mobile & Web Development
  - Flutter, Django, Django Rest Framework, Android
- Database & Operating Systems
  - Linux (Ubuntu), PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Tools & Technologies
  - Docker, Git, LATEX, WebRTC, Scikit-learn, Pandas, Microcontroller Programming, Bash Scripting
- Other
  - Software Systems Engineering, Cross-Platform Application Development

#### **PUBLICATIONS MEDIUM**

- [1] A. Yazdi, "Using Software Engineering methods to design and build a fully responsive and adaptive mobile, desktop, and web application",
  - The first part of the series of the Software Engineering approach in Cross-Platform Programming with Flutter, Flutter Community, Jan 2021.
- [2] A. Yazdi, "Designing and building the Flutter application structure using the Bloc pattern in the micro-service architecture",
  - The second part of the series of the Software Engineering approach in Cross-Platform Programming with Flutter, Flutter Community, Jan 2021.
- [3] A. Yazdi, "Designing and building the Flutter application data models and backend using the Build value and Bloc pattern",

The third part of the series of the Software Engineering approach in Cross-Platform Programming with Flutter, Flutter Community, Jan 2021.

#### **PROFESSIONAL PROJECTS**

The Location-Based Recommendation System, Django, Rest Framework, Scikit-learn, Flutter

A microservice recommendation system recommends by the mixture of content-based and collaboration recommendation algorithms based on user location-based social media networks like Foursquare and Google Map. The services include:

- Django Rest Framework API service.
- Foursquare API connection service.
- Open Street Map location datasets scrapping service.
- Recommendation service.
- Flutter application service using Google Map to show recommendation spots.
- The Flutter Portfolio Application, Flutter

**△ · ▲ · ⊕ · ○** 

Designing and Building a responsive Flutter gallery application for any platform.

■ The Flutter Gallery Application, Flutter

M • 🛎 • 🌐 • 🗘

Designing and Building a micro-service architecture responsive Flutter gallery application for Computer Engineering graduates uses in any platform.

■ The Flutter Media Notification Plugin, Java, Flutter

Designing and Building a Flutter Plugin helps developers show their media notification and control streaming media beyond the Flutter application.

• The Flutter Chat Application, Flutter, SignalR, WebRTC

Designing and Implementing a full-featured (simple message, multimedia message, voice, video) flutter chat application by SignalR and WebRTC.

#### **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

■ NUMEX Interpreter, Racket

Designing a simple interpreter NUMEX programming language with Racket for Programming Languages course.

■ Planet vs Zombies Game Application, Java

A 2d game similar to Plant vs Zombies game using java object oriented programming for Advanced Computer Programmings course.

■ Digital Watch Microcontroller, C

A digital watch with LCD and alarm using microcontroller ATMEGA16 for Microprocessor and Assembly Language course.

• Finite State Machine Search Engine, Java

Creating four types of data structure and searching using AVL-tree, balance-TST, trie-tree and hash Data Structure and Algorithms course.

■ UDP to TCP Proxy, Python

A python proxy that receives HTTP packets on UDP then sends them on TCP with DNS server for Computer Networks course.

Security Course, Racket

(7)

Working on encryption with MD5, SHA256, DES, working with cryptool software nmap and using  $ms08\_067$  exploitand for Information Security course.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

#### Data Structures and Algorithms, Amirkabir University of Technology,

Sep 2017-Mar 2018

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

• Supervisor: Prof. Mehdi Dehghan • dehghan@aut.ac.ir

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

### Artificial Intelligent and Robotics Lab, Amirkabir University of Technology,

Oct 2019 - Oct 2020

Undergraduate Research Student

• Project: Designing and Implementing Location Based Social Network Recommendation System

• Supervisor: Prof. Mohammad Rahmati

• Focus: Artificial Intelligence, Software Engineering, Data Analytics

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Artificial Intelligence

Machine Learning

Software Engineering

**LANGUAGES** 

English: Fluent, working proficiency (Studying IELTS)

Persian: Native language

#### REFERENCES

#### • Ph.D. Student Shervin Rasoulzadeh

Former Colleague at Tarafdari,

Ph.D. Student and Research Assistant, Technische Universität Wien, Faculty of Informatics, Technische Universität Wien, Karlsplatz 13, 1040 Vienna, Austria srasoulzadeh@cg.tuwien.ac.at

#### Professor Mohammad Rahmati

Former Advisor and Supervisor at Amirkabir University of Technology, Professor of Department of Computer Engineering, Amirkabir University of Technology, Dept. Computer Engineering Amirkabir University, Hafez Ave., Tehran, Iran rahmati@aut.ac.ir

#### **HOBBIES**

- Hiking & Travelling.
- Listening Music & Playing a Persian Instrument called 3Tar.
- Playing Football & Volleyball.
- Playing Chess & Video Games.

[*Last Update on 2021-01-24*] • [Clone me on • ]